<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Siddhant Pyasi</title>
    <description>Siddhant Pyasi&apos;s personal website.</description>
    <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://siddhantpyasi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Second Despatch (Two Years Later)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess the first two years were destined to have just one despatch. To be honest, I aimed for this one to come out not long after the first one (I started writing this piece on the 22nd of July, 2023). So, I figured, might as well continue writing it. But my moving finger did not write&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;type, if we’re being pedantic. If Omar Khayyam ever comes to know that I’m twisting his poignant couplets to get eyeballs on the internet, he &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; rise from his grave to have some words with me.&lt;/span&gt; and thus, did not move on. I’ve left the original bit of writing as-is, and have made annotations to it in the sidenotes. Please, enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of overall well-being - I’m good. Busy&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and good.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote successive&quot;&gt;I was a sweet summer child when I wrote this in 2023. Having spent every saturday of the past year in school, getting a part-time degree, I can say I’m busy &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; I’ve gotten used to this city’s rhythms. I did realise fairly early on in my stint that NYC has a pretty solid PR racket going on. This piece will from time to time, crib about things that the PR machinery very conveniently keeps out of the news. When I’m sitting in the Q train and hear the conductor make a sudden announcement saying hello, this is not the Q train anymore, this is actually the F train, I don’t flinch. I stay seated, because muay thai has taught me not to show weakness to anyone&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote successive&quot;&gt;muay thai also taught me how to injure myself in July 2023-ish, and I haven’t kicked a bag since.&lt;/span&gt; least of all to the first city I’ve encountered that has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiswLb1_uP-AhXTUKQEHZEpCToQFnoECA4QAw&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdictionary.cambridge.org%2Fus%2Fdictionary%2Fenglish%2Fnon-deterministic%23%3A~%3Atext%3DMeaning%2520of%2520non%252Ddeterministic%2520in%2520English%26text%3Dlikely%2520to%2520have%2520a%2520different%2Cthat%2520is%2520unstable%2520and%2520dynamic.&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1q8MX45Q1GKYivLievNh6L&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;non-deterministic&lt;/a&gt; subway system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/nyc_skyline.png&quot; alt=&quot;just trying to break this wall of text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m sitting in a bus going somewhere, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w6Chsy5cdkk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kramer-esque fella&lt;/a&gt; pitches me a nice scheme and hands me his business card, I smile and take it, promising to get in touch with him soon. If I see human excrement on the streets, I walk by, with the best air of nonchalance I can muster.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;I’ve seen more human poop on the street here in 7 months than I did in India in 18 years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also the fact that looking for places to rent here can quickly teach you what the word “absurd” truly means. Here’s one instance - remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GX25jrMr3MI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;that episode&lt;/a&gt; in HIMYM, where Marshall and Lily’s apartment turns out to be crooked? Remember how when you first saw the damn ep, you chalked it down to the writers’ table in the show smoking really high quality stuff, writing something over-the-top in the way only HIMYM writers did? So back in Feb I found an apartment in a great location in the West Village, for really cheap, the only problem being the small&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; bedrooms.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;imagine the standard 4 foot by 2 foot trench that infantrymen generally dig at the end of a long, hard day&lt;/span&gt; I figured there was a catch - small bedrooms are, after all, de rigeur in this town. What else was it that kept the price so low? Upon reaching for my viewing, I entered the apartment, and after a while said out loud (within earshot of the realtor), “Is it just me, or is the floor tilted?”, thinking, why would an apartment with a tilted floor ever be thought fit to exhibit to prospective tenants? The realtor just shrugged and said, “it’s an old building”. Oh well. Looked through a bunch of apartments&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and managed to find decent digs in the end. &lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;around forty-ish&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, didn’t mean to come off as someone who changed cities to provide himself with the spice of life&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; only to be mad about the spice he encountered. I was, and remain, a spice enthusiast. I love that there’s a world out there for me to explore.  &lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;i.e., variety&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing cities is the best way to provide yourself with variety&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;an &lt;em&gt;overrated&lt;/em&gt; spice of life&lt;/span&gt; Having changed cities about 10 times in my 26-year life&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote successive&quot;&gt;man, I’d started writing this piece when I’d just turned 26, and now I’m roughly 3 months out from 28. Time flies.&lt;/span&gt;, I’d say I’m somewhat of a spice enthusiast by now. Spice is addictive. It is physically and mentally painful. It numbs your senses, brings excitement to your life, teaches you about regret, and sometimes it gives you a nice story to tell to people at dinner. All in all, it’s not too bad. I will say though that after eating too much sichuan food over a week in Singapore, I cannot really deal with regular spice very well. Metaphorical spice though? Bring it &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/food_colisseum.png&quot; alt=&quot;food and old building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a lot since the last despatch. Went to Italy for the first time - did 11 cities in 11 days: Rome, The Vatican, Palermo, Cefalu, Trapani, Erice, Bari, Matera, Alberobello, Monopoli, Florence. Got into eating clean and lifting weights&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;my PR for deadlifts is 85kg. Aim to get to 100 this year.&lt;/span&gt; Visited Rio and its gorgeous beaches. &lt;!-- Met hellie. --&gt; Tried to learn skiing. Took an elementary spanish class. Saw my cousin married off in Allahabad. Took a dip at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triveni_Sangam&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sangam&lt;/a&gt;. Became much better at writing Python. You know, the works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2025/02/22/observations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2025/02/22/observations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The very first one</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A sweaty brow, an uneasy stomach, and a tentative heart accompanied my first steps&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;a fairly brisk trot, as opposed to the more languid walk employed by most expats&lt;/span&gt; into America. What Wodehouse would call a “concatenation of circumstances” had occurred, and it meant that I marked my arrival to the New World by being cataclysmically sick mere metres&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;still on the metric system, thank god&lt;/span&gt; after I stepped off the plane&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote successive&quot;&gt;that’s right, I couldn’t even make it to the nearest washroom&lt;/span&gt; I blame the fish served on the plane, my mother on the other hand says this is how I lay announce my arrival to inhabitants of foreign lands. Both of us have sufficient empirical evidence to buttress our claims - I know that fish have never been great fans of my gut; I also know that &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; new-to-me places have had the good fortune of being decorated with the contents of my stomach&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;A screening of &lt;em&gt;Koi Mil Gaya&lt;/em&gt; (2003), Simla (2004), Shillong (2009), Ladakh (2017)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. In any case, the 18-hour plane ride was not comfortable, I was unable to sample any of the food Singapore Airlines is famous for (apart from the fish of course), and I arrived at my sister’s&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote successive&quot;&gt;her name is Srishti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; apartment a sweaty, dehydrated husk of a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know when you think you know what a term means, and then someone conducts a demo for you, and only then do you truly &lt;em&gt;internalise&lt;/em&gt; what the term truly means? Well, my arrival was God’s way of demonstrating to me why the word “projectile” is present in the term “projectile vomiting”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, moving on. By this time in an article about arriving at a new place, writers of a certain variety would have used the next few paragraphs to describe their interaction with the fairly chatty taxi driver who drove them, and tried to draw a nice pithy conclusion about the state of the world from the said interaction. Yours truly, however, was, a) driven by a driver who didn’t say a single word throughout the ride, and b) was taught statistics by the formidable &lt;a href=&quot;https://faculty.smu.edu.sg/profile/rosie-ching-2211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rosie Ching&lt;/a&gt;, so he knows what happens when one tries to draw conclusions about things from studies with small sample sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, Srishti and I dragged all of my stuff over to the corporate housing apartment&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;splendid digs located at Liberty View, Battery Place&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that had been booked for my first month in NYC. Now, corporate housing can be a double edged sword. It is a great source of comfort when you land. It is also a great source of discomfort when you start looking for apartments and realise that you have a ways to go before you can afford to live in that sort of style, or space. In any case, by my second night in the fancy apartment, I missed Singapore so much that I walked about a kilometre away in pouring rain&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to the only establishment in NYC that made me feel like I was back in Singapore for a little bit - Shake Shack. And I’m pleased to report that the Shake Shacks here are just as good as the ones in SG. &lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;I put on my ski jacket and took advantage of its waterproofness (waterprooficity? I don’t wanna say water resistance)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two weeks passed by in a blur denser than the fog that envelopes your glasses when you get out of an air conditioned car.  I learnt quite a few things in those two weeks. I learnt that people jabbing themselves with needles in subway cars are not doing it to get their daily dose of insulin, generally. I learnt that setting up a Twitter list&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; called “NYC” and filling it up only with Fire Department and Police Department tweets is a great way to turn into Chicken Little’s distant Indian cousin.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;for the uninitiated, a Twitter list is basically a feed with specific Twitter accounts&lt;/span&gt; I also learnt that you develop peripheral vision rather quickly if you have the aforementioned Twitter list and look at it every 20 minutes&lt;span class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;hey, I have better peripheral vision now. That’s a win in my book&lt;/span&gt; Lastly, (and this is something that affected me more than it should’ve) I learnt that Manhattan doesn’t have any decent Chinese food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more learnings (some quite major), which will come in a second piece, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/lDojqc8WeegAAAAC/bombshell-clarkson.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Thank you!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2023/04/07/arrival/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2023/04/07/arrival/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Acid Reflux Dam Returns, and a cool BMW</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s some new material to chew on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethiopia’s built a dam called the GERD&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on the Nile river, which is threatening the &lt;em&gt;very existence of Egypt&lt;/em&gt;, what with Egypt being the ‘Gift of the Nile’ and all. Generally, if you threaten the existence of a country, the country will do its best to stop you from doing that. Which means war, &lt;a href=&quot;http://siddhantpyasi.com/DST00020#GERD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as I wrote in November&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam (GERD). GERD also stands for Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease, which is basically really severe acid reflux.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around November, trouble erupted in the Tigray region of Ethiopia. The Tigrayans had unresolved issues with the Ethiopian government, and soon the region descended into a civil war, leading to the displacement of ~2.5m people, with both sides committing several war crimes. That’s not all. The countries of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.power-technology.com/comment/tigray-conflict-grand-ethiopian-renaissance-dam/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eritrea and Sudan have been dragged into the conflict&lt;/a&gt; too - Eritrea because it’s been overtly helping the Ethiopians against the Tigrayans, and Sudan because all the displaced Ethiopians have taken refuge in Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The war comes at a good time for Egypt. It’ll want for Ethiopia to remain weak and distracted internally, so that Egypt can dominate the negotiations around the dam. The longer it takes Ethiopia to deal with the Tigray issue, the better. Of course, if Ethiopia manages to figure out a solution quickly, it’ll end up appearing &lt;em&gt;stronger&lt;/em&gt;, and that’s not desirable for Egypt at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were running Egypt, I’d do my best to help the Tigrayans out. I suspect Egypt is doing something of that sort; it is one of the few sensible things that can be done from their perspective. Sure, Egypt’s been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/4/7/egypt-warns-ethiopia-of-potential-for-conflict-over-blue-nile-dam&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;making noises about going to war&lt;/a&gt; over the dam, but no country wants outright war - wars are expensive, messy and tough to end once started. The only way out of this mess that I see is if some regionally ambitious country (Saudi Arabia, UAE, Turkey, etc.) steps into the mix and makes the two countries negotiate. The ideal end result would be some sort of water sharing agreement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indus_Waters_Treaty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;like the one India and Pakistan have&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s cool car that will definitely appreciate in value is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bringatrailer.com/listing/2002-bmw-z8-31/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2002 BMW Z8&lt;/a&gt;. It was designed as an homage of sorts to the original good-looking Beemer, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/BMW_507&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;507&lt;/a&gt;, which was catastrophic for BMW when it was introduced in the late ’50s, financially speaking, sending the company to the edge of bankruptcy. But, it looked &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;. It was one of those cars that just radiated a sort of timelessness with its curves. By the way, a 507 in good condition today will set you back by atleast $2m, if not more. Which is why we turn our attention to the Z8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BMW built ~5,700 of the Z8s, which is a nice number - it is large enough for these cars to still be affordable today, and small enough for these cars to become scarce a decade or so down the line. Even back then, BMW intended for these cars to end up with collectors, which is why it guaranteed spares for them for 50 years. And, it’s a manual! Oh, imagine driving it with its top down, slotting the gear lever into the right spot, and giving the 4.9l V8 the beans. As of the time of writing this piece, the bid for this car was at $161,000. If you’re interested in bidding, I’d say a safe bid would be around $180,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Covid situation in India is pretty bad, and way too many people have tested positive. Please do whatever it takes to save yourself from this ghastly disease, people. All the best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/04/12/DST00023/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/04/12/DST00023/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Margin Calls, Location Tracking and a Hot Ferrari</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s some new material to chew on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not gonna talk about that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/30/powerful-tugs-and-an-ebbing-tide-how-the-ever-given-was-freed&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stupid ship blocking the Suez Canal&lt;/a&gt; because clearly &lt;em&gt;that ship has sailed&lt;/em&gt;, heh heh.&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt; I will say one thing, though. This is exactly why countries have navies. While this was an accident, it is entirely possible for some country to lose its marbles (I mean, look at the neighbourhood the canal is in) and block the canal wilfully. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re an Investment Banker at Credit Suisse (CS). You worked your ass off all year, working insane hours to generate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/led-by-mr-spac-credit-suisse-cashes-in-on-blank-check-spree-11612527389&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fat fees through SPAC deals&lt;/a&gt;, etc. You’re looking forward to a juicy bonus at the end of the year, your reward for all those all-nighters. Maybe you’ve even decided on a Rolex to buy, and the Rolex AD has reserved your piece for you - all you need to do is head down to the shop to pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on Monday you learn that some dope in CS’ Prime Brokerage (PB) unit lent a bunch of money to a guy who’d been fined once for insider trading, and who was leveraged 5-to-1 (i.e., with $16 billion of capital, dude had bought $80 billion worth of paper). The gent in question was unable to pay back his debts, and CS was one of those left to pay the tab - to the tune of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/credit-suisse-in-firing-line-after-archegos-losses-11617117154741.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$4 billion dollars&lt;/a&gt;, although some say that the loss might go as high as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AlessioUrban/status/1376831414012944385?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$7 billion&lt;/a&gt;. So you might have to say bye to that Rolex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several PBs (Goldman Sachs, CS, Nomura, UBS, Morgan Stanley, Deutsche, BNP and Citi) were involved in servicing the fund in question, named Archegos Capital. The story we’ve heard so far is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Archegos was unable to pay a margin call.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because Archegos had bought swaps, the shares that the banks had bought could not be held by the PBs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These shares would be sold to make good any demands the PBs had over Archegos, and the rest would have to be made up by the collateral Archegos had placed with the banks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if so many PBs would’ve sold so many shares at once, the market for those shares would’ve collapsed, and the PBs would have ended up losing more money - which is why all the PBs tried to organise an orderly sale of Archegos’ swap shares to minimise damage for all involved. That initiative failed when one bank (hint - the film &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margin_Call&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Margin Call&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was made on the same bank, when it had done something similar - it got out of the market before anyone else woke up) just straight up pressed the “Sell Everything Now and Screw The Rest” button, leading to a panic. CS is still figuring out exactly how much they lost, Nomura announced that they lost $2 billion, even Mitusbishi UFJ said that they might &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.straitstimes.com/business/banking/as-archegos-losses-are-tallied-up-regulatory-scrutiny-grows&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;take a hit of up to $300 million&lt;/a&gt;. They’re still figuring out how much money they’re losing, so these amounts might change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a good sign - if one family office hedge fund was running around with so much leverage, are there others out there? What if banks decide to ask the others to cut down on &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; leverage - will the combined selling that’ll happen cause problems in the markets? What if this episode is just a prelude, and there’s a bigger, more leveraged fund out there that’s gonna get fried, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long-Term_Capital_Management&quot;&gt;Long-Term Capital Management&lt;/a&gt; style? Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out cars track A LOT of your data with you not even realising it. There are several telematics sensors in cars, which transmit data to manufacturers / data-providers quite regularly. A company called The Ulysses Group claims it has access to a fair bit of that data, and it can provide any paying customer with the ability &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/k7adn9/car-location-data-telematics-us-military-ulysses-group?TrucksFoT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to find the location of cars in every country except North Korea and Cuba on a near-real-time basis&lt;/a&gt;. Which is why I think I’m gonna stick to buying old cars that were completely mechanical and did not come with any creepy location tracking sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which reminds me, one asset class that’s taken off quite well is old cars. If you’re looking for a good car to &lt;em&gt;park&lt;/em&gt; your savings in and also avoid creepy telematics tracking, might I recommend this &lt;a href=&quot;https://bringatrailer.com/listing/1978-ferrari-308-gt4-4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1978 Ferrari 308 GT4&lt;/a&gt;. Last I checked, someone had bid $51,000 for it. Which is a lot, considering the fact that in 2005, the 308 was featured in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GuCff8nCxBU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;episode of Top Gear&lt;/a&gt;, where one of the presenters had bought a &lt;em&gt;1979&lt;/em&gt; 308 GT4 for around $17,000. That works out to an annualised return of approximately 8%. Not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Older Ferraris have suddenly become ‘hot’, with some Ferraris (like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://bringatrailer.com/listing/1973-ferrari-dino-5/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dino&lt;/a&gt;) going for an insane $350k! The 308 in question is also a Dino, technically. Ferrari had released the 308 as a Dino in 1973. In ‘76, they dropped the Dino moniker and slapped the prancing horse badge on it instead. I think the price will only appreciate further as the original Dinos become more expensive and people turn to collecting the cheaper ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the long weekend ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/03/31/DST00022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/03/31/DST00022/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overworked Analysts, India and China, and Undersea Shenanigans</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello,
Been a while, huh. I would like to wish you all, belatedly, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy Diwali &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Merry Xmas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy New Year, and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy Lunar New Year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right. On to business - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/documents/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/rim9z3X.NpYk/v0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;slide deck made by harried juniors at Goldman Sachs’&lt;/a&gt; Investment Banking (IB) Division has been doing the rounds the past week, and it makes you want to pity them, till you remember the fact that they’re actually very well compensated for their troubles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the bit that makes you pity ‘em - they’re working 105 hours a week on average. Their mental health is suffering. Some choice quotes like the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I didn’t come into this job expecting a 9am-5pm’s, but I also didn’t expect consistent 9am-5am’s either”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt; ”My body physically hurts all the time and mentally I’m in a really dark place”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;help add some more colour to their situation. I’m pretty sure humans were not designed for 100-hour weeks, that’s just inhuman.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, they really should not be surprised. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://epicureandealmaker.blogspot.com/2013/11/the-invention-of-leisure.html?m=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this writer&lt;/a&gt; tells us, in rather colourful language, anyone joining an IB should remember that - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… the core premise of my industry … is &lt;em&gt;uncompromising customer service&lt;/em&gt;. The entire f______g point of working 24 hours a day, for days on end, and canceling weeknight dates with Kate Upton, Las Vegas bachelor parties with George Clooney and Brad Pitt, and Christmas holidays with the Pope of all Christendom at the last possible minute is that &lt;em&gt;the entire investment bank works at the pleasure and whim of clients who pay us a small fortune to do so&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison, one is reminded of medical residents, who work just as long for lower pay, and are responsible for the lives of actual human beings too. It must suck, though, to think you’ll join an Investment Bank and work in a high octane environment, where every fibre of your being would be engaged in finding the best terms for your client, only to find out that PowerPoint and Excel do a really bad job of supplying the aforementioned high octane, and that every fibre of your being is actually just adjusting box sizes and fonts to suit your MDs idiosyncrasies.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much will change. Certain walks of life - law, medicine, banking, etc. have always had such working hours, and there have always been very many people willing to call themselves members of those professions, and by extension, work those inhumane hours. Oh and by the way, the CEO of Goldman has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-14/goldman-ceo-s-year-of-empty-offices-island-getaways-and-strife?sref=mGcsJ2E3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;made his displeasure known at the whole work-from-home thing that’s besieged the working world&lt;/a&gt;, and he would very much like it if people came back to office. Heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China and India have ‘disengaged’ on the India-China border in Ladakh. The standoff has been pretty long, and for a while there both countries’ militaries were locked in an eyeball-to-eyeball confrontation. The man in charge of India’s Northern Army said that the two countries &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shreyadhoundial/status/1362055976422023168?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;almost went to war on the night of 29-30 August&lt;/a&gt;, when India deployed its own troops to check China’s aggression.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also know now that the way the People’s Liberation Army (PLA) had deployed itself (in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gunnersshot.com/2021/02/sino-indian-logjam-aim-gone-astray-by.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;straight lines&lt;/a&gt;) indicated that they did not anticipate an Indian reaction; they definitely did not anticipate a reaction that would lead to shots being fired (which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/china-again-attempts-to-close-in-on-indian-positions-warning-shots-fired-in-ladakh-1722230-2020-09-16&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;also happened&lt;/a&gt; on the night of 29-30 August). Here’s hoping that that part of the world remains relatively calm for the foreseeable future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a site that’ll make you sit up and think - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.submarinecablemap.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Submarine Cable Map&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shows you the routes along which cables have been laid on the sea-floor. Made me wonder about just how many choke points there were for these cables - and how easy they might be to mess with should someone decide to put their minds to it. Oh wait, that’s already been done! Many years ago, the US spent millions of dollars and built a nuclear-powered ‘special projects’ submarine named the USS Halibut, which sailed all the way to the coast of the USSR, and tapped submarine cables laid by the Soviet navy, recording &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Ivy_Bells&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;years’ worth of conversations&lt;/a&gt;. The whole operation was discovered, however, through typical Russian ingenuity - they paid a disgruntled American a paltry US$35k, and he told ‘em all about the operation. Objectively speaking, the Russians won that round, hands-down (on a Return-on-Investment basis, that is). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s more where that came from, and I’ll send it all out soon enough. Thank you for reading, hope you have a great week ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/03/22/DST00021/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2021/03/22/DST00021/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Weird Car, a New US President, and an Acid Reflux Dam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s another milestone - 20 newsletters! Thank you all for reading what I write. I fell into a bit of a stupor the last couple of months, so I’m trying to start this thing again. Let’s see how long I last. This one’s gonna be shorter than usual. Here goes -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another weird car. You know how millions of drivers are terrorised by their better halves to drive under a (completely arbitrary) speed limit? Well, Chevrolet decided to do their bit in helping the spouses keep their maniacal other halves under control. They built a very unique system into the new Chevy Corvette (which is absolutely stunning, by the way) that stops the car from going beyond 80mph (128.7 kmph ish). What’s the system? A malfunctioning door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Corvette has a trunk in the front (because the engine is in the middle of the car). Because of a manufacturing defect, the trunk’s door has been known to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hN7jQPjNcY8&quot;&gt;open inadvertently sometimes&lt;/a&gt; (YouTube link), and if the trunk is open, the car’s speed is limited to 80mph by default, because GM doesn’t want you driving around like a jackass with your front trunk door open, unable to see anything, at more than 80mph. The company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.automobilemag.com/news/2020-chevrolet-c8-corvette-recall-frunk-stop-deliveries/&quot;&gt;ended up voluntarily recalling&lt;/a&gt; all cars delivered thus far to fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, I would like to leave you with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NwLJWQQfSU&quot;&gt;sound of the Corvette’s glorious 6.2 litre V8&lt;/a&gt; (this video is not for the weak, i.e, the Tesla lovers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump lost, Biden won (although if some people are to be believed, and I am one of them, Trump won’t leave so easily - but let’s assume that he will). Good for Biden, I wish him luck. My view on the election - the US is incredibly polarised right now. The best thing that could have happened to the US was a centrist getting elected - because only a centrist can coax and cajole the two different parts of the country to come together as one. Remember, Trump still managed to get a little more than 45% of the total number of votes cast. What does that mean?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means that the people who voted for Trump are not idiots, as opposed to what Saturday Night Live and all the other reductionist Late Night show anchors (and people who live in the large urban agglomerations on the East and West Coasts) would have you believe. The 45% see Trump for what he is, but they have more pressing issues to think of. Their jobs have left American shores, never to return. More jobs may now leave, because the world is open, and there are people in Vietnam who will do your job for a fraction of the rate they’re charging. The social mobility that made America the land of opportunity is probably gone, too, unless they have the ability to take crippling amounts of educational debt to gamble on themselves, hoping to build a life that was hopefully better than the ones their parents had. Add to this volatile mix some idiotic left-leaning Democrats going around chanting “defund the police” - even though the police have kept your small town safe thus far, with no untoward incidents happening. All in all, not a good state of affairs.  The only viable candidate (thanks to the 2-party system) who they thought addressed their issues was Trump, and if he came with his warts and all, then so be it. Therefore, calling this 45ish percent of the electorate “stupid” will not help. They have genuine needs, needs that have not been addressed by the people they’ve chosen to lead them thus far.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Biden - do not alienate these people, please. Do not make the mistake of treating them as the unwashed, illiterate masses that the US is saddled with. Accept their anxieties, and work with them. And do not, for god’s sake, do not let yourself be pulled in by the “left” in your party (which you have very smartly and successfully managed to avoid doing throughout your campaign) - you’re a centrist, stay that way. And before anyone hits “Reply” on this email to complain about why Democrats are the ones who are always asked to compromise, may I remind you - a Dem won this election. Which is why it is the Dems who will have to compromise, simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b id=&quot;GERD&quot;&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
Egypt and Ethiopia are not on the best of terms right now. Ethiopia has been building what it calls the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam (GERD - by the way, GERD also stands for Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease, where yes, you guessed correctly, one gets a lot of acid reflux) for a while now, and sometime last month, they announced that they’d begun to fill the GERD’s reservoir.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does one build a dam? To control the flow of water along a river. And what about the people living downstream of a dam’s proposed site? Will they be impacted? Well, if those people belong to another country, then that’s just too bad. Which is pretty much how Egypt ended up getting shafted by Ethiopia’s acid-reflux-dam.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egypt is called “the gift of the Nile” and it contends that the dam will lead to droughts because Ethiopia’s gonna store all the water from the river, leaving Egypt with very little. Egypt’s not the only country that has a problem with the dam - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/africa-in-focus/2020/08/05/the-controversy-over-the-grand-ethiopian-renaissance-dam/&quot;&gt;Sudan’s affected too&lt;/a&gt;. The three countries have been in talks about it, and at one point the US got involved, when Trump warned the Ethiopians that Egypt might “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-54674313&quot;&gt;blow up&lt;/a&gt;” the dam, and he’d be powerless to stop them from doing so. Needless to say, the Ethiopians weren’t chuffed. The latest round of talks between Egypt, Ethiopia and Sudan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/11/5/egypt-ethiopia-sudan-fail-to-succeed-in-disputed-dam-talks&quot;&gt;broke down&lt;/a&gt; recently. The talks are about coming up with an agreement on sharing water between the three countries, and so far, Ethiopia does not seem to want to budge. We hope for the best, then, because the last thing the world needs right now is a fight over water (which, is a very likely scenario in my view because the challenge to Egypt from the dam is almost existential in nature - and when someone’s backed against a wall like that, the only way out is to fight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all we have time for today, and a new one shall come out soon! Take care and stay safe, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/11/11/DST00020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/11/11/DST00020/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Turkey&apos;s still screwing around, a very weird car, and Lebanon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! New week, new Daily Something. Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last edition, I had written about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://siddhantpyasi.com/DST00018&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turkish survey ship, the Oruc Reis&lt;/a&gt;, and how the Turkish government had held off sending it into Greece’s territorial waters. Well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tcsavunma/status/1292883501075910656&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;they sent the ship in&lt;/a&gt; along with escort ships, and some sort of a nautical scuffle ensued between the two nations. Apparently a Hellenic (Greek) Navy frigate &lt;a href=&quot;https://defpost.com/greek-navy-frigate-collides-with-turkish-navy-frigate-escorting-research-vessel-oruc-reis-reports/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collided with a Turkish Navy frigate&lt;/a&gt;. In times like this, when you know nothing of what actually happened, each side’s going to claim a sort of victory - Greece says that it was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ekathimerini.com/255853/article/ekathimerini/news/standoff-peaks-with-incident-in-east-med&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turkish escort ship that messed up received heavy damage&lt;/a&gt;, while Turkey says that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ekathimerini.com/255834/article/ekathimerini/news/erdogan-says-greece-attacked-oruc-reis-got-their-first-answer-today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greece was taught a good lesson&lt;/a&gt;.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do most leaders get aggressive with their neighbours? Generally speaking, they do it to shore up a rapidly eroding domestic power base. History tells us that if you (the beleaguered leader of a country) paint a third party as an aggressor, you can sort of get your own people to forget whatever differences they had (temporarily), and unite in your support, to fight against said third party. The great Mao Tse Tung put this to good use in the 1962 war with India. George Bush’s approval ratings went through the roof after 9/11 (although he wasn’t exactly beleaguered then, but you get what I’m saying). And between you and me, I think Xi Jinping’s having a lot of trouble within China, which is why he’s picking fights with all of his neighbours, trying to show them as aggressors. There’s a term for this effect, by the way - it’s called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rally_%27round_the_flag_effect&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rally ‘round the flag effect&lt;/a&gt;.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_battles_involving_France_in_modern_history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the eternal fighter&lt;/a&gt;, sent in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/08/mediterranean-crisis-turkey-warns-greece-slams-bully-france-200814140628522.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;couple of jets&lt;/a&gt; to exercise with the Greeks, in a show of strength. She also sent a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csmonitor.com/World/Europe/2020/0813/Why-France-is-sailing-into-a-Greece-Turkey-territorial-dispute&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;couple of ships&lt;/a&gt; to accompany the Greeks. We might see Italy do the same too. The only way to deal with Erdogan (who is willing to risk a war here), is to band together with other European nations, prepare to take casualties, and fight. Nothing less will do.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear that Erdogan is creating crises where none exist. But their effectiveness will only be seen in 2023, which is when the election for Turkey’s next President will be held. This particular conflict won’t last till then (all conflicts have a best-before date). Unless, Erdogan calls for early elections. Then this just might work.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a car nut. Always have been, and always will be. So you can imagine how pained I must be when I see people do weird things with cars. Here’s the weird car thing of the month - &lt;a href=&quot;https://jalopnik.com/theres-actually-a-decent-reason-why-germans-will-spend-1794673235&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the ellenator conversion&lt;/a&gt;. And no, this does not mean that you install a TV in the car that plays The Ellen Show all the time. It means you take a really small car, and bring the two rear wheels of the car close enough that the car becomes a three wheeler. And you also add a speed governor in the car so that it doesn’t go faster than 50 km/h. To cripple your perfectly nice car in this way costs $5000. Here’s what it looks like &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ellenator.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Fiat 500 in the Ellenator conversion&quot; /&gt;
(Image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/whatisthiscar/comments/i2l24l/what_is_this_strange_arrangement_of_wheels_under/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;) What a joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this is that you give your 16 year old a vehicle that’s safer to drive than a Vespa (why not just give the kid a bicycle and make the kid work their quads and hamstrings?), because in Germany you can drive a three wheeler at the age of 16, without a full driving license. But there are better ways to spend the $5000! Just wait for 2 years and buy them a better car. Make ‘em ride cycles till then. Your kids will thank you, because they won’t have skinny legs, and they’ll have a nicer car. And then, if you wanna buy your kids a safe car, just get them a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyantgroup.com/where-does-volvos-reputation-for-safety-come-from/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A horrific blast rang out at a harbour in Beirut, Lebanon, killing 158 people, and injuring 6,000. The damage it caused can be seen by the before and after photos, which have been taken from this article -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Beirut_before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before&quot; /&gt;
Before&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Beirut_after.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;After&quot; /&gt;
After&lt;br /&gt;
(images taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-53686563&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crater caused by the blast was 43m deep, which is roughly equivalent to a 10-floor building. Some workers were allegedly welding a gate in Warehouse 12 at the port in Beirut, and behind that gate were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/aug/07/beirut-explosion-former-port-worker-says-fireworks-stored-in-hangar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;30-40 nylon bags of fireworks&lt;/a&gt; that had been confiscated by the authorities back in 2009. Warehouse 12 also stored 2,750 of highly, highly, highly explosive ammonium nitrate confiscated by the authorities in 2014. One thing led to another, and the fireworks exploded. Soon, they were joined by the ammonium nitrate. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rezaparchizadeh/status/1292505677156487169?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mass destruction followed&lt;/a&gt;. Mass destruction followed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was common knowledge to the Lebanese government and judicial system that such a large quantity of explosives was placed in the harbour for so long, yet nothing was done about it. Beirut now looks at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enr.com/articles/49905-beirut-wrestles-with-blast-damage-estimated-at-up-to-15-billion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rebuilding bill that’s anywhere between US$10 to US$15 billion&lt;/a&gt;. The Lebanese people are angry because their government &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/after-the-beirut-explosion-volunteers-step-up-to-do-what-the-government-cant-11598034057&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;didn’t do much to help them out post the blast&lt;/a&gt;, and the fact that the government bureaucracy is largely regarded as corrupt. The government’s situation was not helped by the fact that Lebanon is currently experiencing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tatianakoffman/2020/07/09/lebanons-currency-crisis-paves-the-way-to-a-new-future/#11f1ec2a6a17&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hyperinflation&lt;/a&gt;, wiping out the savings of most of the country’s population. Thus, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/08/lebanon-pm-hassan-diab-resigns-anger-beirut-blast-200810135202076.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;country’s Prime Minister resigned&lt;/a&gt; on the 11th of August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event could be the catalyst for Lebanon to change for the better. The people could come together, vote for a better government, and that government will have to take tough decisions to lift the country out of the hole it has dragged itself into. It’d be hard at first, but slowly, things could, and would change. Here’s the catch, though. People in Lebanon can’t really come together. They had a 15-year-long civil war because of this quality of theirs. Lebanese society is deeply fragmented by religion - they have Sunni Muslims, Shia Muslims, Christians (very many denominations), and Druze. It is because of this fragmentation that certain posts in the government are reserved for people from certain religions (which, as we have learnt from the British rule in India, almost always has the effect of emphasising the divisions between people). Thus, what we have on our hands is a properly messy, tangled situation. One can hope against hope and experience that someone transformative will come along to set things right (and such people do exist - Marshall Tito of Yugoslavia was one very good example), but they don’t come along often, you know. For now, I pray for Lebanon and its people. May you someday regain your past glory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have some more free time, you can listen to an “architecture critic” rant about how interior design across the world is becoming standardised and boring because of Airbnb &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/6996e7f2-7446-43e5-9c31-2606b9e316b7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time. Take care, and stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/08/10/DST00019/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/08/10/DST00019/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Racketeering, Turkey and Greece, and Drew Pavlou</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, as promised, here’s TDS number 18, in a record time of 17 days. It’s been a year since I started to write this series of newsletters! The &lt;a href=&quot;http://siddhantpyasi.com/DST00001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;first one&lt;/a&gt; had come out on 31 July 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the United States, there exists a weird word used to denote any form of organised criminal activity - racketeering. I don’t know, the word just sounds really funny to me. After a lifetime of hearing the word “racket” in the context of noise - “oh those idiots made a hell of a racket last night”, the very word racketeering brings to my mind an image of a couple of professional noisemakers, doing their best to try and demolish everyone’s eardrums.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republican speaker of the Ohio House of Representatives, Larry Householder, was indicted on charges of racketeering last week. Now this dude &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newarkadvocate.com/story/news/local/2020/08/02/fbi-claims-householder-60-m-into-1-3-b-energy-bailout-personal-gain/5556655002/&quot;&gt;took roughly $60m&lt;/a&gt; from a nuclear energy company (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firstenergycorp.com/fehome.html.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FirstEnergy&lt;/a&gt;) to shepherd a bill through the House of Representatives that would bail out FirstEnergy to the tune of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2020/07/30/larry-householder-indicted-bribery-case-house-speaker-job-stripped/5544693002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$1.3 billion&lt;/a&gt;. I’m sure that the people at FirstEnergy saw this as a very nice call option - pay $60m, and get a payoff that is a little more than 20x. But I think they didn’t calculate the downside correctly - it is not just $60m, but the additional cost of litigation as well as reputational risk that would come if this scheme were discovered. A lot of times the downside we see isn’t the real downside, there’s always a bit more. The next time you want to bribe someone, keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkey and Greece are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-07-25/here-s-what-is-at-stake-as-turkey-greece-tensions-rise-again?sref=mGcsJ2E3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not happy&lt;/a&gt; with each other right now. The facts are these - almost a 100 years ago, the Treaty of Lausanne was signed between Turkey (which had just become a republic) and France, England, Italy, Japan, Greece and Romania. The treaty settled the borders of Turkey, and led to the new Turkish state being recognised by the international order. It also brought stability to that part of the world - Turkey focussed on reconstruction and reformation post World War I, and Greece knew that the Turks would abide by the treaty, so they went back to having siestas and fiestas, only to be surprised by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Greece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;German invasion&lt;/a&gt; in the second world war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erdogan does not like this treaty. He doesn’t like the fact that the treaty gave to Greece several islands that Greece uses to claim an Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ) that is more than what the Greeks are entitled to. Back in 2017, on an official visit to Greece, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/dec/07/turkish-president-erdogan-to-make-landmark-visit-to-greece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he surprised his hosts&lt;/a&gt; by saying as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the map below (taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/europe/2020/08/01/turkey-and-greece-avoid-coming-to-blows-for-now&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in The Economist). The island of Kastellorizzo, which is barely 800 metres away from Turkey, belongs to Greece. Because the island belongs to Greece, they claim the surrounding waters too for Greece’s EEZ. How much area do the Greeks claim? An area 4,000 times larger than the area of the island. For its part, Turkey says that the calculation of EEZs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailysabah.com/opinion/columns/kastellorizo-one-of-turkey-and-greeces-interrelated-controversies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;should happen from the mainland, and not from some random far-flung island&lt;/a&gt;. I get Erdogan’s point here - it all seems terribly unfair to Turkey. But I also see the Greek point of view. &lt;em&gt;And the waters here are supposed to contain oil and/or gas&lt;/em&gt;. So dollar signs are flashing in front of both Greece and Turkey right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Turkey Map.png&quot; alt=&quot;El sceno de crimo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late last month, Erdogan announced his intention to send a Turkish survey ship, the &lt;em&gt;Oruc Reis&lt;/em&gt;, into the Greek territorial waters to conduct some surveys.  Turkey has one of the larger navies in the region, so Erdogan definitely had the muscle to back up his threat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having frazzled Greece, and by extension, the European Union (EU) thusly, Erdogan received a phone call from the one and only Angela Merkel. Long story short, he announced that for now, no survey will happen, pending further negotiation. If all goes well, the Greek foreign minister will pay a visit to Turkey sometime in the fall. Stay tuned for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drew Pavlou is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/work-and-careers/education/student-senator-will-make-life-hell-for-university-of-queensland-20191025-p534be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-righteous, indiscreet, grandiose and disobedient&lt;/a&gt; 20-year-old student at the University of Queensland (UQ), Brisbane, one of Australia’s premier universities. Because of all the adjectives used to describe him, you may have guessed by now that he belongs to a class of people commonly known as the “student activist”. Last year, he organised a protest against what was happening in Hong Kong. Counter-protesters (in this case, people favouring China) showed up, and Drew was, uh, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7315119/University-Queensland-student-attacked-pro-China-activists-bombarded-death-threats.html#v-4360862607029812596&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;treated roughly&lt;/a&gt;. Soon after, he got elected to UQ’s senate (which, by the way, is a pretty sweet gig that pays AU$50,000 per year). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Drew didn’t want a cushy gig, from the looks of it. He wanted UQ to donate his salary to the cause of Uyghurs being repressed in China, and when the uni disagreed, he called them names, never mind the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/work-and-careers/education/student-senator-will-make-life-hell-for-university-of-queensland-20191025-p534be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he could just donate the money to the cause himself&lt;/a&gt;. Soon after getting elected, he announced that he will work towards getting the Confucius Institute at UQ shut down (I don’t think he could, though? Student leaders get a lot of publicity, but they rarely have very many substantive powers). Drew also wanted UQ to end its association with a Chinese consul general, who had been given an adjunct professorship by UQ. Are serving diplomats from other countries given professorships at universities? I don’t think so. There’ll be plenty of retired diplomats running around in academia, but never serving ones, that too in countries different from their country of origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, at the peak of the COVID scare, our man Drew pulled up at the Confucius Institute at UQ wearing a hazmat suit, holding a board that said the Confucius Institute was a “biohazard”. Soon after, he received notice of an inquiry against him, and a 186 page booklet detailing his crimes was delivered to his doorstep. He was charged with violating university policy, and last I heard, he has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2020/jul/13/queensland-student-drew-pavlous-suspension-reduced-but-will-remain-out-of-university-until-2021&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;suspended for 2 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put aside the “student activist” facade of Drew for a second, and really listen to the points he’s making. Drew’s unhappiness at the PRC stems from their ever increasing influence on academia in the western world. China funds &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confucius_Institute&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Confucius Institutes&lt;/a&gt; at universities throughout the world, with the stated purpose of increasing awareness about the Chinese language and culture. So in a way, the Confucius Institutes are similar to, say, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alliance_fran%C3%A7aise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alliance Francaise&lt;/a&gt;? Yes and no. Yes in that language classes are offered there. No because the Alliance Francaise institutes operate independently - they don’t tack themselves on to a college campus. It is the presence of the Confucius Institute at college campuses that has caused issues for universities. The universities want the money that the institutes bring in, but with the money comes Chinese interference. What sort of interference? They &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-peoples-republic-of-queensland-11590015806&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pressure students&lt;/a&gt;, they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/education/2019/nov/05/alarming-chinese-meddling-at-uk-universities-exposed-in-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pressure professors&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/df27ad90-017d-11ea-b7bc-f3fa4e77dd47&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pressure some more professors&lt;/a&gt;, whenever the students/professors talk about issues that China is sensitive about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tough problem to have. How does a university administrator keep a campus open to opposing viewpoints, minimise violence, minimise pushback from an aggressive nation many miles away, minimise pushback from the university’s own nation, and keep the university running well, financially, since the aggressive nation from far away sends a lot of students that pay fat fees? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, more coming up soon. Thank you for taking the time to read it, and please feel free to give me any feedback you have. And of course, take care, and stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/08/02/DST00018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/08/02/DST00018/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unclaimed baggage, Tik Tok getting banned in India, and a deadly India-China clash</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, the last month-and-a-half has been a &lt;em&gt;little hectic&lt;/em&gt; at work, and there’s a sort of backlog of things I wanted to talk about, so I didn’t want to write a really long newsletter, which is why I removed some stuff that I’ll put into another newsletter that will come out sometime this month (I swear it will).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of stuff that people never claim from the airlines. Where do you think it goes? To the aptly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unclaimedbaggage.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unclaimed Baggage&lt;/a&gt; (UB) company in Scottsboro, Alabama, apparently. UB has an exclusive contract with several airlines to take all of the unclaimed baggage they are left with and do whatever they want with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty professional operation, having been in service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unclaimedbaggage.com/pages/our-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;since 1970&lt;/a&gt;. One imagines that the company is mostly saddled with bags filled with clothes (which they dry-clean and re-sell or donate to the needy), but they find a lot of weird stuff too. Right now, they have on sale &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unclaimedbaggage.com/products/lambs-m-219-mens-underwear&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;radiation-proof boxer briefs (size M, US$15.99)&lt;/a&gt; and a scuba diving computer, among other things. In case you’re looking for a bargain, you know where to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/india-bans-tiktok-dozens-of-other-chinese-apps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;India banned 59 chinese apps&lt;/a&gt;. TikTok, CamScanner, and WeChat are among those that are not allowed in India. This ban was a result of the fighting that happened on the India-China border sometime in mid-June (more details in the next segment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the widespread popularity of Chinese phones and apps in India, this order is supposed to impact 1 in 3 mobile phone users in India, as the link mentioned above says. Because of growing anger in India against China, this move by the government has been accepted by most people as a necessary step, although funny TikTok videos made by Indians that were all the rage on the internet won’t be seen anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about TikTok, here’s a fascinating Reddit &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/fxgi06/not_new_news_but_tbh_if_you_have_tiktiok_just_get/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; by a guy who reverse-engineered the TikTok app. And here’s another Twitter user trying out iOS 14, who says that TikTok is &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/fxgi06/not_new_news_but_tbh_if_you_have_tiktiok_just_get/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;grabbing the contents of his clipboard every 1-3 seconds&lt;/a&gt;. WTF? I’d like to thank god and my sense of procrastination for having never installed TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about what’s happened over the past couple of months at the India-China border, between the Indian Army and the Chinese Army (Peoples’ Liberation Army - PLA). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India and China are separated by a line called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_of_Actual_Control&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Line of Actual Control (LAC)&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ladakh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ladakh&lt;/a&gt; region. Notice how that line isn’t called the “border”. This is because the two nations went to war in 1962 over a disagreement on where the border actually lay; China won the war and the two sides decided to call whatever line they were actually separated by the LAC. For over 40 years now, there’s been a sort of “understanding” that the LAC is the effective border, but even the LAC is perceived differently by the two sides. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elmihiro/status/1265701027891699713/photo/1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This graphic&lt;/a&gt;, made by Twitter user Mihir Shah should give you a good idea of the sort of mess we’re dealing with here with regard to the border situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime in April 2020, Chinese soldiers patrolling the border came in a little too deep inside the Indian side (it was later learnt that this was pre-planned). When confronted by Indian soldiers, they refused to leave, and there was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/india-china-brawl-video-sikkim-decoded-lac-ladakh-galwan-psyops-1692003-2020-06-23&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pushing and shoving and punching between troops of both sides&lt;/a&gt; (there is another “understanding” that guns will not be fired at the LAC - an agreement was signed between the two countries in 1996 about it). Having just gone through all that, you can imagine that tensions were high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the skirmishes, senior officers of the two countries met on 6 June, and agreed to disengage. It was pointed out to China that they had built some structures/tents on the Indian side of the LAC, which China accepted and agreed to demolish. The area with these structures came under the responsibility of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/B._Santosh_Babu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colonel B Santosh Babu&lt;/a&gt;, the Commanding Officer (CO) of the 16th Battalion, Bihar Regiment (16 BIHAR). So it was his responsibility to check and confirm that the tents had indeed been demolished by the Chinese. There were other units in the area too - 3rd Battalion, Punjab Regiment (3 PUNJAB), and two artillery regiments - 3rd Medium Regiment and 81st Field Regiment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime later, on 15 June, it was brought to Col Babu’s notice that a new tent had been set up at the spot of the demolished tent. He set out to investigate along with a party of around 30-40 men from 16 BIHAR and 81st Field Regiment. They saw the tent, argued with the Chinese soldiers, and the argument developed into a fight, which ended with the demolition of the tent. The Chinese soldiers were rounded up by Col Babu, and deposited on the Chinese side of the LAC. But the Indians had walked into an ambush. In the darkness, Chinese soldiers lay in wait for them, and more fighting happened. The Indians called in reinforcements from 16 BIHAR, 3 PUNJAB, 3rd Medium and 81st Field regiments. In the darkness, Col Babu was hit by a stone flung by the Chinese, and died. This angered the Indians, who fought back even harder. It has been reported that the Chinese troops were armed with sticks studded with nails and barbed wire, to get around the restriction on guns imposed by the 1996 agreement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the fight ended, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/3-separate-brawls-outsider-chinese-troops-more-most-detailed-account-of-the-brutal-june-15-galwan-battle-1691185-2020-06-21&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;16 dead bodies were handed back to the Chinese&lt;/a&gt;, which included the body of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/chinese-army-confirms-their-commanding-officer-was-killed-in-ladakh-face-off-during-military-level-talks-in-galwan-sources-2250280&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chinese commanding officer as well&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://theprint.in/defence/these-are-the-20-soldiers-killed-in-action-in-galwan-after-clashes-with-chinese-troops/443441/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;20 Indian soldiers lay dead, including Col Babu&lt;/a&gt;. 10 Indian soldiers were captured by the Chinese, and an unconfirmed number of Chinese troops were captured by the Indians. After a couple of days of talks, both sides released their captives, and began to dig in on either side of the LAC. To date, the Chinese have not released the exact number of men killed or injured, although a couple of website posts here and there point to some discontentment in China about the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aadilbrar/status/1275517989497044994&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the funerals for their dead were kept private&lt;/a&gt;, while in India &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=denlaUU8t9M&amp;amp;t=22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thousands turned up to mourn each of the dead&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per reports, India has moved &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/army-moves-3-divisions-tanks-to-ladakh-sector/story-rObj7wvAR6HtwbuJ5AdpXM.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3 divisions&lt;/a&gt; (roughly 30,000 men) into that area, along with planes and tanks. One imagines a similar quantity of men and equipment on the other side of the border. Both sides are now talking to each other, but for now, this is the “new normal” for the India-China border. For the gain of a few square kilometres of area, China has gained the distrust of 1.2 billion Indians.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions remain to be answered for the Indian side, though. Why did India have no inkling of what was about to happen? Why did we “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bsdhanoa/status/1283248018825703425?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;trust&lt;/a&gt;” the Chinese in the first place to stick to their side of the border? If China can think of moving against India so brazenly, it is only because no costs have been imposed on it by India. Does India have the ability to impose costs on China in the first place? If it does, then why did China move against India? Why has the Indian military run off on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/amid-border-row-india-allows-armed-forces-to-speed-up-weapon-purchases-worth-rs-300-crore/story-IpOpM5AiJeBz2w9PyhWncO.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;weapon-buying spree&lt;/a&gt; all of a sudden, when previous Army chiefs said that we were prepared to fight a war on two fronts? And who is to be held accountable for letting China enter Indian territory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you are. I do not doubt the commitment of the Indian military here. But these are quite glaring questions that arise, and they must be answered at the earliest, so that this doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry for writing out such a long one. The next one’s going to be shorter. Take care and have a great week ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/07/15/DST00017/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/07/15/DST00017/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>India-China boundary issues 101</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After finding myself lost a bit too many times about the whole India-China border episode, I decided to educate myself on the subject. Because I’m a chap who likes to do the world a bit of good, I have decided to pass on my very vast knowledge to you, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin, then. There’s a lot of reading involved, and if you’re not the reading type, too bad. The following resources were used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/Chinas-India-War-Collision-Course/dp/0199475555&quot;&gt;Bertil Lintner - China’s India War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.claudearpi.net/the-sino-indian-boundary-issue&quot;&gt;Claude Arpi’s - The Sino-Indian Boundary Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/Choices-Shivshankar-Menon/dp/0143429116/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=shivshankar+menon+choices&amp;amp;qid=1591017729&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;Shivshankar Menon - Choices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/TopSecretdocuments2.pdf&quot;&gt;The Henderson-Brooks, Bhagat Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And this wonderful website called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chinaindiaborderdispute.wordpress.com/articles-on-sino-indian-border-dispute/&quot;&gt;China-India Border Dispute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this is a blog post, it is not going to be excessively detailed. But it will have all you need, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/06/01/Educating-Myself-About-China/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://siddhantpyasi.com//2020/06/01/Educating-Myself-About-China/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
